Michael Kelly

Email: michael@kelly.media - Phone: 541-203-0711 - Location: Amston, Connecticut LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/michael-kelly-media/ - Github: github.com/kellymedia Developer Portfolio: tiny.cc/developer-portfolio - Creative Portfolio: tiny.cc/creative-protfolio

SUMMARY

Junior Web Developer and Mid-level Graphic Designer, demonstrated strong communication and collaboration skills and interested in problem solving and project management. Experience with strategic working and major marketing campaign development for large academic institutions and recreation industry retail companies. Have worked on brand-identity development and re-branding projects for small to medium businesses and helping clients to develop social media and online strategies. Interested in finding opportunities to use my creative and coding skills to help improve audience engagement and user-experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React.js, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Adobe CC, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Premiere Pro, WordPress, PHP, cPanel, phpMyAdmin, Google Analytics & Ads, Facebook Business Manager, Hootsuite, Zoom, G Suite, Microsoft Office

WORK EXPERIENCE

National Intramural-Recreational Sports Association

January 2015 - June 2020

Digital Services Coordinator

(Remote) Corvallis, Oregon

- Created digital and print media assets for multi-dimensional marketing campaigns geared for national markets.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to develop UX case studies and implementation and communicated project timelines and traffic analytics using Google Marketing Platform; Scheduled social media and tracked engagement with Hootsuite, 1,800,000+ collective page-views, 2019. Managed VPS hosting and third-party plugin integration and maintenance, 99% uptime.
- Contributed to news production and publishing e-newsletter; averaged 3,800 recipients bi-monthly, 55% average click-rate, 2019.
- Remote employee agreement, 2016-2020.

First Alternative Co-op

January 2015 - August 2017

Graphic Designer

Corvallis, Oregon

- Created internal and external marketing assets, in alignment with National Grocers Cooperative (N.C.G.) brand guidelines.
- Managed website content production and maintenance; managed all social media channels and audience engagement.
- Coordinated media assets production and product promotions with vendors, including planning and promoting special events.
- Assisted brand-identity rebrand and designed new outdoor signage, 2015. Designed and launched rebranded responsive website, 2016.
- Remote web-consultant agreement, 2016-2017.

Yogurt Extreme LLC

February 2010 - May 2012

Restaurant Manager

Corvallis, Oregon

- Developed scalable operational safety and training procedures; responsible for hiring and training staff; managed 30+ employees.
- Oversaw staff weekly scheduling and food/beverage inventory for each location.
- Worked directly with the owner to construct and open three self-serve yogurt restaurant locations in twenty-four months.

Oregon State University

September 2009 - November 2010

Corvallis, Oregon

- Facilitator Created and facilitated leadership, team building, and problem-solving exercises for large groups utilizing outdoor education methods.
 - Trained and certified in professional climbing and adventure park risk mitigation practices.
 - Facilitated effective communication and safe-space protocols in high-risk and challenging environments.

Nielsen Media Research

June 2007 - June 2008

(Remote) Middletown, Connecticut

- Technical Field Representative
 - Installed and maintained viewership equipment in volunteer households participating in "Nielsen TV Ratings" market surveys.
 - Performed software and hardware upgrades for networking and communications equipment used to track survey viewership habits.
 - Remote employee; responsible for management of storage location, expense reporting, and equipment shipping and receiving.

EDUCATION

University of Connecticut - Hartford, Connecticut School of Engineering - Coding Bootcamp Full Stack Web Development Certificate

Expected, September 2020

Linn-Benton Community College - Albany, Oregon

June 2014